<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OAuth 2.0 on Fabian Hauck</title>
    <link>https://fabianhauck.de/tags/oauth-2.0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OAuth 2.0 on Fabian Hauck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fabianhauck.de/tags/oauth-2.0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OAuth 2.0 and OpenID Connect for Penetration Testers</title>
      <link>https://fabianhauck.de/blog/oauth_for_pentesters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fabianhauck.de/blog/oauth_for_pentesters/</guid>
      <description>OAuth 2.0 and OpenID Connect are playing an important role in modern applications. OIDC is used for authentication whereas OAuth is used to grant access to protected resources. Therefore, it is important to correctly implement and harden those techniques against malicious actors.
This presentation gives a short introduction to OpenID Connect and OAuth 2.0 and describes the most important flows. After that, common attacks and their mitigations are shown and in the end, there is a summary and an outlook on new developments in the OAuth community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving OAuth App-to-App Security</title>
      <link>https://fabianhauck.de/blog/improving-app2app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fabianhauck.de/blog/improving-app2app/</guid>
      <description>OAuth flows on mobile devices can benefit a lot from native apps. With native apps, for example, it is possible to use already existing sessions and biometric authentication features. While apps improve the user experience, they also bring new security challenges to OAuth, especially for services like open banking. This document describes the challenges of redirections between native apps and web applications on Android and iOS and recommends solutions based on currently available features of the mobile operating systems and browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
