<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fabian Hauck</title>
    <link>https://www.fabianhauck.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fabian Hauck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fabianhauck.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Data Security and Privacy</title>
      <link>https://www.fabianhauck.de/blog/security_privacy_workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fabianhauck.de/blog/security_privacy_workshop/</guid>
      <description>Wenn du wissen willst, wie du dich im Internet vor Hackerangriffen und Spionage schützen kannst, dann bist du in diesem Workshop genau richtig! Die behandelten Inhalte sind für alle relevant, die ein Smartphone oder einen Laptop besitzen.
 Die Digitalisierung hat in den letzten Jahren unser Leben massiv verändert. Durch die Corona-Pandemie wurde diese Entwicklung zusätzlich stark beschleunigt. Während einerseits viele Dinge vereinfacht werden, entstehen andererseits neue Gefahren. Die Anzahl der Cyberangriffe ist im letzten Jahr rasant angestiegen und fast jeden Tag kann man in den Nachrichten von neuen Angriffen lesen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OAuth 2.0 and OpenID Connect for Penetration Testers</title>
      <link>https://www.fabianhauck.de/blog/oauth_for_pentesters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fabianhauck.de/blog/oauth_for_pentesters/</guid>
      <description>OAuth 2.0 and OpenID Connect are playing an important role in modern web applications when it comes to security. OIDC is used for authentication, whereas OAuth is used to grant access to protected resources. Therefore, it is important to implement those techniques correctly and harden them against malicious actors who want to steal the access tokens.
The following presentation gives a short introduction to OAuth 2.0 and OpenID Connect and describes the most important protocol details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving OAuth App-to-App Security</title>
      <link>https://www.fabianhauck.de/blog/improving-app2app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fabianhauck.de/blog/improving-app2app/</guid>
      <description>OAuth flows on mobile devices can benefit a lot from native apps. With native apps, for example, it is possible to use already existing sessions and biometric authentication features. While apps improve the user experience, they also bring new security challenges to OAuth, especially for services like open banking. This document describes the challenges of redirections between native apps and web applications on Android and iOS and recommends solutions based on currently available features of the mobile operating systems and browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Security Awareness Training</title>
      <link>https://www.fabianhauck.de/blog/security_training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fabianhauck.de/blog/security_training/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, 60 percent of the world&amp;rsquo;s population has access to the internet1). Users spend on average three hours a day online2) with shopping, browsing social media, or doing bank transactions.
While using online services, it is always important to keep your data and accounts secure. If you do not pay attention to what you are doing online, you can easily be attacked by hackers as the attack on the iCloud of Jennifer Lawrence a few years ago showed3).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
